FRANCISCO JAVIER TORMO CASTAÑO

ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING INTERNSHIP



ABOUT ME

I am a driven 22-year-old engineering student from Elche, entrepreneur, and innovator, with an avid interest in developing my STEM proficiencies. My focus lies in promoting responsibility and teamwork, and I am keen to lead a tech team in devising innovative solutions and addressing challenges towards achieving a meaningful objective.

TECHNICAL SOFTWARE

- Matlab, Phyton, C++, LaTex.
- · SolidWorks, AutoCad, JMAG.
- SimuLink, SimScape, PowerSystem.
- · Excel Macros, LTpice, PSim.
- · Mathematica, CLEAmt. Vijeo, Zelio

LICENSES

Driver's license, Motorcycle, Food handler.

LANGUAGES

• English, Spanish, Catalonian, French.

DEVELOPING SKILLS

- · Analysis and problem-solving
- · Comprehension and integration
- · Application and practical thinking
- · Professional responsibility
- · Permanent learning and innovation
- · Multidisciplinary and leadership
- · Teamwork and empathy
- · Ethical and positive attitude
- · Creativity and entrepreneurship

PERSONAL INTERESTS

• Education:

Math, Physics, Astronomy, Electronics, Efficiency, Economics, Business, Urbanism, Investment.

· Creativity:

Guitar, Piano, Reading, Writing, Poetry, Photography.

• Sports:

Padel, Hiking, Cycling, Motorbike, Travel.



- · Benimaclet, Valencia
- · Elche, Alicante



javitormocas@gmail.com



672 49 57 93





COLLEGE EDUCATION

UNIVERSIDAD POLITÉCNICA DE VALENCIA (UPV)

Electrical Engineering Degree: 2021 - Now

- Currently studying **3-4rd** year.
- · Mastered: Simulink, PowerSystem, Excel, C++, CLEAmt, OrCAD

Civil Engineering Degree: 2020 - 2021

- Finished 1st with 3 honors, 8.2 grade point avg and best academic record award.
- · Mastered: Matlab, AutoCAD, Mathematica

LONG-TERM STUDENT ACTIVITIES

HYPERLOOP UPV, Generación Espontánea

Electromagnetics Engineer : Oct 2023 - Now

- Created a detailed synthesis on DLIM(double sided linear induction motor) operation, with a focus on principles and control through FOC(field oriented control) and V/F(voltage frequency escalar).
- Caracterized DLIM&HEMS 2D/3D on JMAG through transient, frequency and static analysis.
- Assumed the rol of Lead Developer for Charging and Transformer Systems
- Attending the international competition EHW at the Zurich Innovation Center this summer.
- · I love competition, engineering, and designing new technology!
- Mastered: JMAG, Simulink, LTSpice, AutoCAD, SolidWorks, LaTex

EOLIA UPV, Generación Espontánea

Power System Engineer: Sep 2023 - Now

- · A wind turbine competition.
- Analyzing asynchronous vs. shunt motor specs.

77

7

23

PROLUO UPV, Generación Espontánea

Chief Economics Manager: Sep 2021 - Sep 2022

emer beonomies wanager . Sep 2021 Sep 2022

- Led a team of 6 while developing technical and legal skills in a larger team of 32 engineer students to reach our roadmap.
- Built a new inventory database that allowed the team to increase total productivity
- Reduced material costs by implementing a price-quality comparator system.
- · Looked for new efficient suppliers minimizing management times
- Established numerous financing channels resulting in more than €5,000 fund.
- Established relationships with large organizations related to the project values.
- I love innovation, economic management, and making a better world!
- · Mastered: Excel Macros, Team Leadership, Economic Management.

DEGREE COURSES AND PROJECTS

Relevant Courses:

- · Control of Machines and Electric Drives.
- · Electromechanical Drive Technology.
- Power Electrical Systems.
- · Power Electronics.
- · High-Voltage Electrical Installations.
- Low Voltage Electrical Installations.
- Electric Traction.
- Industrial Regulation and Automation.

Relevant Projects:

- High Voltage Power Line Project: Simple circuit with aluminum-steel conductor 100-AL1/17-ST1A.
- Design of an Off-Grid Electrical Installation with Photovoltaic and Wind Power.
- Powering the Future: Incorporating Doubled-Sided Linear Induction Motors in Hyperloop UPV Prototypes.

ENTREPRENEURSHIP CONTESTS

- Top 5 out of 35 projects in 2k23 UPV's Business Idea Competition by Ideas UPV.
- Accepted into the Santander X Explorer program.
 Attended Gennera Competition by Ideas UPV.
- Attended Day-Emprende by Ideas UPV.
- Attended VLC Tech Xperience 2023.
- Hackaton Iberdrola Abril 2024

1

FRANCISCO JAVIER TORMO CASTAÑO

ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING INTERNSHIP

22

22

7

8

19

9

2



SANTANDER X EXPLORER

- Santander's entrepreneurship program focuses on providing support to an entrepreneurial project to develop a Minimum Viable Product (MVP) with the possibility of crowdfunding.
- AutoVision Tech is a project dedicated to transforming urban mobility through real-time augmented reality navigation solutions for businesses. Our goal is to improve safety, save time, and reduce costs, ultimately creating a more efficient urban environment.

INTERNATIONAL EXPERIENCE

Interrail in Europe 2023

- Visited 9 European countries: France, Italy, Switzerland, Austria, Germany, Denmark, Sweden, Netherlands and Belgium.
- Multilingual Communication: Demonstrated English and French communication skills in multilingual environments showcasing adaptability and effective communication.
- Technical Immersion: Explored renowned museums gaining insights into historical and contemporary engineering marvels enhancing understanding of technological advancements.
- Agile Problem-Solving: Managed a 25-day itinerary, overcame unexpected train disruptions and logistic problems. This highlights composure under pressure, quick decision-making, hard adaptability and resourcefulness.
- **Personal Growth:** Gained independence, confidence, and the ability to thrive in unpredictable situations, valuable assets for any engineer.

Key Skills Demonstrated

- Technical Curiosity & Understanding
- · Problem-Solving & Resourcefulness
- Adaptability & Communication in Diverse Environments
- Decision-Making & Time Management under Pressure
- Independence & Initiative

ADDITIONAL OVERVIEW

Technology

- Operated and assembled multiple Arduinos for circuit and robot integration on high school.
- Collaboratively designed and built a BB-8 robot with a team of four for a technology fair.
- Designing linear motors and levitation units for Hyperloop UPV.
- Refined skills in HTML, Arduino, Linux, MATLAB, and C programming environments.
- Developing a comprehensive personal website showcasing past work and projects.

Business Analysis

- Broadened knowledge in finance and business administration through ADE and Marketing courses and self-learning.
- Demonstrated versatile digital skills as a web creator on Shopify.
- Implemented multiple payment gateways on business including Stripe, PayPal and Klarna.
- Proficient in SEO, online ads, email marketing, and other digital techniques with experience at Zeuta.
- Experienced in analyze and invest in public trade companies by evaluting financial statements, cash flow, future earnings growth and dividends.

Creative Design

- Launched and took the lead as the main content creator and editor for social media pages centered on photography, finances, science, humor and poetry.
- Conceptualized all kind of creative logos, announcements, drawings, covers and flyers and headed the creative design at Zeuta.

JOB EXPERIENCE

O BURGER KING, Valencia

Home Delivery Coordinator: Jun 2022- Ago 2023

- Led a 13-member delivery team by providing clear direction, coaching, and mentorship to promote efficiency and collaboration, resulting in successful task completion.
- Enhanced productivity by efficiently executing up to 150 daily orders, utilizing effective time-management and prioritization skills.
- Contributed valuable abilities while working within a 30-member team, fostering a collaborative and supportive work environment.
- I love optimization, motorcycles, and satisfied customers!
- · Mastered: Excel, Team Leadership, Optimization.

SUSHI SHOP, Valencia

Waiter & Delivery Man: Ago 2021 - Jun 2022

- Directed 3 delivery drivers to streamline processes.
- Reduced delivery times by 31% and gas costs by 16% through street route analysis.
- Enhanced abilities while working alongside a skilled team of 16.
- Completed courses in first aid, hazards prevention, and customer service to improve job performance.
- · Cultivated positive relationships and environment among colleagues.

ZEUTA ONLINE STORE, Valencia

Head Coordinator: 2019 - 2020

- Directed a team of 4 data technicians to consolidate the information system.
- Analyzed purchase patterns to aide sales team in developing marketing campaigns.
- · Headed the creative design on social media and website.
- Successfully implemented loyalty card and pay-per-click campaigns resulting in a 42% increase in customer retention and €15,000 in sales within two weeks.
- Performed up to 40 daily orders and 30 daily emails from potential customers.
- Mastered: Google Analytics, Google Ads, FB Ads, IG Ads, Shopify, Stripe, Copywriting, SEO, Marketing, Web Design.

EL CASTILLO CARWASH, Aspe

Assistant: 2015 - 2019

- · My father's business.
- Minimized customer complaints in order to maximize customer satisfaction
- Digitalized business by implementing a website on Google Site, Google Business, Google Maps and Facebook.

